Erik Hirsch

Apple Valley, CA 92308

Phone: 760 420-4308 | Email: ehirsch760@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/e-hirsch | GitHub: github.com/eh4git

Portfolio: erik-hirsch.com

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with previous management experience and a passion for problem solving and collaboration. Effectively communicates with others to streamline the development cycle to produce polished applications. Known by peers for having a strong work ethic and being determined to produce the highest quality results possible.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6

Technologies: Node, React, React Native, Redux, MySQL, Seguelize, MongoDB, Mongoose,

Express, ¡Query, BootStrap, Semantic, Materialize, Handlebars.is, Ajax, Sass, AWS

Projects

Along With Me - January 2021

Available on the Google Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rnapp2021 Digital book companion enhances readers' experience through audio that accompanies the text.

- Mobile application built with React Native
- Users are authenticated using Firebase Authentication
- Global state is managed by Redux
- User information and personal settings are stored in Firebase

Key Role(s): This project has open roles allowing for work on all areas of the application.

Technologies: React Native, CSS, JavaScript, Firebase

Once Upon An Adventure - July 2020

www.onceuaa.com | github.com/eh4git/once-upon-an-adventure

A collection of educational mini games within an RPG style browser game.

- JavaScript and canvas html elements utilized in the creation of educational mini games.
- Integrates MongoDB to provide data persistence.
- Implemented React for the front end UI incorporating hooks and Redux to manage state.
- Node and Express used to create back end logic that handles Ajax requests.
- Secured user accounts implement brrypt to hash and salt passwords.

Key Role(s): Animation of sprites, music, and sound effects

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Howler, Ajax, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Redux

Story Time - June 2020

github.com/eh4git/StoryTime | fathomless-waters-70908.herokuapp.com Personalized children's story generator.

- Responsive Bootstrap UI allows users to easily navigate while using the application.
- Developed front end logic using ¡Query.
- Integrates MongoDB to provide data persistence.
- Node and Express used to create back end logic that handles requests.
- Secured user accounts implement brrypt to hash and salt passwords.

Key Role(s): HTML, JavaScript, Front end logic

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Ajax, MongoDB, Express, Node

Experience

Freelance Developer Third Project Development

2020 - Present

CA

Develop full stack web and mobile applications to client's request.

Consult with client's to determine the best course of action for their application.

Enumerator 2020 - 2020

US Department of Commerce - Bureau Of Census

Victorville, CA

- Strong communication skills used to engage and connect with the public.
- Work 100% independently to complete daily tasks.

Delivery Driver United Parcel Service 2019 - 2020

Victorville, CA

- Recognized for strong work ethic.
- Awarded by management for achieving highest performance on multiple occasions.

Project Manager

2015 - 2019

Rick Kittson Hardwood Flooring

Irvine, CA

- Supervised a small team to maintain quality and to complete projects in a timely manner.
- Recognized for strong work ethic.

Cooling Operator

2017 - 2018

Golden Island

Rancho Cucamonga, CA

- Reduced labor costs by 50% through assisting in the implementation of new cooling systems and procedures.
- Attained recognition for excellent attendance record.

Education

UCLA Extension - Los Angeles, CA

Full Stack Web Development - Certificate

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.

Victor Valley College - Victorville, CA

Management Certificate of Completion - Certificate

31 Unit program that teaches the skills that are required for management. Courses included Accounting, Economics, Computer Literacy, Human Resource Management, Legal Environment of Business, Business Math, and Business Communications.

Additional Courses

Scrimba

The React Boot Camp - August 2020, Tricky Parts of JavaScript - September 2020, Learn Regular Expressions - September 2020

Amazon Web Services

AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials, Introduction to AWS Storage Gateway, Introduction to Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3), Amazon Simple Storage Service - Closer look - Part 1&2, AWS Storage Offerings